# Jinbin Hu | Curriculum Vitae

Department of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
Hong Kong SAR – China

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
Hong Kong SAR – China

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

\*\*Hong Kong SAR – China\*\*

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

\*\*Hong Kong SAR – China\*\*

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

\*\*Hong Kong SAR – China\*\*

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

\*\*Hong Kong SAR – China\*\*

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

\*\*Prepartment of CSE, The Hong Kong University of CSE, The Hong University of CSE,

I am currently a Post-doctoral from Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong SAR, advised by Prof. Kai Chen. My current research interests lie in the field of data center Networking, including congestion control, load balancing and RDMA networking, etc\*.

#### **Education**

PostDoc, Dept. of CSE, HKUST

Computer Science and Engineering

Advisor: Prof. Kai Chen.

Ph. D., School of Computer Science and Engineering, Central South University

Computer Science and Technology

Advisor: Prof. Jiawei Huang.

M. S., School of Electronic and Information Engineering, Beijing Jiaotong University

Microelectronics and Solid State Electronics

Advisor: Prof. Xiaoguang Li.

B. S., School of Electronic and Information Engineering, Beijing Jiaotong University
Electronic Science and Technology

Beijing, China
9.2004–7.2008

### **Experiences**

Changsha University of Science & Technology Changsha, China Lecturer 12.2021-Teaching and researching in School of Computer and Communication Engineering. **Hunan Mechanical & Electrical Polytechnic** Changsha, China 12.2021-8.2014 Lecturer Teaching and researching in School of Electrical Engineering. National University of Defense Technology Changsha, China FPGA Verification Engineer 8.2013-8.2014 Responsible for FPGA verification of multi-core CPU in Microelectronics Institute. Empyrean Technology Co., Ltd Beijing, China 1.2011-8.2013 IC Software Test Engineer Responsible for IC simulation software testing.

<sup>\*</sup>Last Updated Jan. 2022

## **Publications**

1.	Adjusting Switching Granularity of Load Balancing for Heterogeneous Datacenter Traffic	
1.	Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang*, Wenjun Lv, Weihe Li, Zhaoyi Li, Wenchao Jiang, Jianxin Wang and Tian He.	6.2021
	IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, 2021, 29(5): 2367-2384.	
2.	CAPS: Coding-based Adaptive Packet Spraying to Reduce Flow Completion Time in Data Center	
	Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang*, Wenjun Lv, Yutao Zhou, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, 2019, 27(6): 2338-2353.	10.2019
3.	RPO: Receiver-driven Transport Protocol Using Opportunistic Transmission in Data Center	
	<b>Jinbin Hu</b> , Jiawei Huang, Zhaoyi Li, Yijun Li, Wenchao Jiang, Kai Chen, Jianxin Wang and Tian He.	11.2021
	In Proc. IEEE ICNP, 2021.	
4.	AMRT: Anti-ECN Marking to Improve Utilization of Receiver-driven Transmission in Data Center	
	<b>Jinbin Hu</b> , Jiawei Huang, Zhaoyi Li, Jianxin Wang and Tian He. In Proc. ACM ICPP, 2020.	8.2020
	TLB: Traffic-aware Load Balancing with Adaptive Granularity in Data Center	
5.	Networks  Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Wenjun Lv, Weihe Li, Jianxin Wang and Tian He.  In Proc. ACM ICPP, 2019.	8.2019
	CAPS: Coding-based Adaptive Packet Spraying to Reduce Flow Completion Time	
6.	in Data Center  Jinbin Hu, Jiawei Huang, Wenjun Lv, Yutao Zhou, Jianxin Wang and Tian He.  In Proc. IEEE INFOCOM, 2018.	4.2018
7.	Coding-Based Distributed Congestion-Aware Packet Spraying to Avoid Reordering in Data Center Networks	
••	Jinbinh Hu, Chang Ruan, Lei Wang*, Osama Alfarraj, Amr Tolba. IEEE Access, 2021, 9: 35539-35548.	3.2021
	Survey on traffic management in data center network: from link layer to application layer	
8.	Weihe Li, Jingling Liu, Shiqi Wang, Tao Zhang, Shaojun Zou, <b>Jinbin Hu</b> *, Wanchun Jiang, Jiawei Huang.  IEEE Access, 2021, 9: 38427-38456.	3.2021
•	Motion Prediction Based TDMA Protocol in VANETs	
9.	Jinbin Hu, Wenjun Lyu, Shaohua Zhong and Jiawei Huang*. Electronics, 2020, 9(11), 1792.	3.2021
(*	stands for Corresponding author.)	

 $(^*$  stands for *Corresponding author.*)

## Research Project

• The National Natural Science Foundation of China

Study on Transport Control in Data Center Lossless Network Based on Priority-based Flow Control, 2022.1.1-2024.12.31